<posts>

<data>
<title>Parents' Night Oct. 29th</title>
<date>2014-10-22 19:41:32</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday October 29, from 7-9 PM, Newton's combined high school FIRST Robotics Team, the Ligerbots, will hold a meeting for parents in the Newton North High School Film lecture hall (the room is located to the left of the Tiger Drive entrance of Newton North right under the staircase).  At the meeting, students and coaches on the team will present what the team is, how the team functions, and how the year will progress. We especially invite parents of new team members, as well as parents who think their children might be interested in robotics, business, and design; parents of returning students are also encouraged to attend, meet the coaches, and learn more about our plans for the upcoming year.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Eat Frozen Yogurt and Support STEM</title>
<date>2014-12-02 20:03:16</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;The Ligerbots is having a fundraiser this Thursday at the Yogurt Beach store in Newtonville.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Come to Yogurt Beach, 665 Watertown St., on Thursday and mention the Ligerbots, and the team will receive 30% of your purchase price.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Last year's robot will be on hand for demos from 5-10 PM.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Please come out and support STEM education in Newton and have some great yogurt.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>LigerBlog: Monday, Dec 1</title>
<date>2014-12-03 19:02:16</date>
<body>
&lt;h3&gt;Hello All! Apologies for the absence of posts last week.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started off Monday's meeting with a name game. Max ran the meeting: we collected money from Candy Box sales, and discussed our upcoming fundraiser at Yogurt Beach (see the handy-dandy flyer at the bottom of the post for more info). If you can volunteer to present the robot between 5pm and 10pm this thursday, email Ben Gross. After that we took a photo for the South yearbook and split into groups. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outreach:&lt;/strong&gt; Created a basic promotional flyer to be used for many LigerBots events. Created a basic template for this year's business plan &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chassis:&lt;/strong&gt; Started cutting the bottom plates out of plywood so it will clear the brackets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery Box:&lt;/strong&gt; Finished up/corrected problems in the CAD. Established need for half-inch plywood instead of three-quarters. Decided how to mount wheels. Worked on structural supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming:&lt;/strong&gt; Worked on downloading code onto the Robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;***Remember: No Meeting on Thursday! Go to Yogurt Beach instead!***&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;3 Lily&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Welcome Google!!!</title>
<date>2014-12-19 15:13:37</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;As of Friday December 19th 2014 LigerBots, Team 2877 is sponsored by Google.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Happy Holidays</title>
<date>2014-12-24 00:17:31</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays, and best wishes for the new year from the LigerBots.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Whole Foods Fundraiser</title>
<date>2014-12-29 23:43:50</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Newton's award winning high school robotics team!!!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
          Last year, LigerBots was ranked 8th in New England and advanced to the world championships in St. Louis. However, competition is a costly undertaking; on any given year, competing in the qualifiers alone costs the team around $20,000.00 between build costs and competition fees. Last year our costs were close to triple that amount, due to travel and added competition fees. Due to our high cost of operation,&lt;strong&gt; we count on support from our community&lt;/strong&gt; in order for the team to continue operation. Throughout the entire month of January, the team will be having a fundraiser at Whole Foods Market on Walnut St. &lt;strong&gt;(916 Walnut Street, Newtonville, MA 02461)&lt;/strong&gt;. Our goal for this fundraiser is to raise $1,000.00 by the end of the month. Members of the team will be present at Whole Foods after school and on weekends to talk about the team, and about FIRST. Donation coupons of varying amounts will be available for purchase at checkout. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check in periodically for updates on the fundraiser, updates on the team, as well as answers to frequently asked questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your support.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Breakfast at Whole Foods</title>
<date>2015-01-30 21:54:43</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;On the morn of  Saturday January the  31st,  the LigerBots organized a morning breakfast celebration, at the Whole Foods located  in Four Corners, from 9 to 11 AM. Thank you for enjoying pancakes, bagels and other breakfast foods, and supporting LigerBots. We raised over $500.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>LigerBots Excel in the 1st Competition of the Season!</title>
<date>2015-03-15 18:41:27</date>
<body>
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7643/16824176942_6cbcd88d57_z.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="Chairman's Award" /&gt; &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend at UMass Dartmouth, the Newton LigerBots, FIRST Robotics Team 2877, turned in an excellent performance in their first district meet of the 2015 Robotics Competition season.  The team made it all the way to semifinals in this year's 'Recycle Rush' game, with their alliance finishing third in the tournament. They also won the coveted District Chairman's Award, an award celebrating FIRST teams' efforts to spread interest in STEM in their community. The accolade also automatically advances the team and the robot to compete in the upcoming District Championship to be held at Worcester Polytechnic Institute on April 9-11, for the chance to qualify for the FIRST World Championships later this spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also at UMass Dartmouth, three members of the team were nominated for and advanced in the competition for individual awards. Congratulations to head coach Charles Hurwitz for advancing to the district championship level for the Woodie Flowers Award for FIRST team mentor achievement, and to Max Tepermeister and Ilias Vamvakas for advancing to the district championship level for the Dean's List Award for FIRST team member achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the LigerBots are ranked 44 of 175 teams in New England, with one qualifying tournament yet to be played at Northeastern University, on March 27-28. Come down to Northeastern or WPI to cheer the LigerBots on.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>The LigerBots Rise to the Top of the New England Region</title>
<date>2015-04-14 21:16:26</date>
<body>
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7638/17140657412_20c441c7d5_z.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="Chairman's Award" /&gt; &lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our competition at Northeastern from March 27-28, FRC team 2877, the LigerBots, were chosen to be part of the second seed alliance along with team 1768 and 663; with our new teammates, we made it all the way to the finals which ended in two very close matches. After our performance at Northeastern, our team moved on to the regional championships at WPI which took place from April 9 to 11. After an intense series of 120 qualification matches, The LigerBots became the captain of the sixth seed alliance and chose team 230 and 558 to participate with us. During Quarterfinals match 2, the LigerBots received a standing ovation when
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X-IgM9Dp7-A&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=1m12s" target="_blank"&gt;we righted Team 558, Robo Squad's, robot&lt;/a&gt; after they had tipped over. The competition at WPI was intense and we congratulate all 60 teams that participated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the awards ceremony, the LigerBots won the regional Chairman's award and secured our place as one of the top 10 New England teams to qualify for St. Louis. The Chairman's Award is given once at each district competition for to the team that best represents a model for others to emulate, and embodies the purpose and goals of FIRST. At the regional championships, all the district winners are given a chance to compete against the other recipients; however, only four presentations are chosen to compete in St. Louis against teams from all over the world. In order to receive this prestigious award, a group of students must showcase the work they have done for the community by creating a written response to present directly to a panel of judges and to film a video demonstrating the impact we have made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the LigerBots are hoping to perform just as well at St. Louis, and are currently raising more funds to help get the team there.
If you wish to donate to the LigerBots, please go to &lt;a href="http://ligerbots.org/support.php"&gt;http://ligerbots.org/support.php&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>FIRST® LEGO® League Information Night</title>
<date>2015-06-14 10:56:27</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in robotics for your elementary or middle school student?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LigerBots invite you to find out more at an information night for FIRST LEGO League (FLL®) - robotics for 4-8th grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday, June 24th&lt;br /&gt;
7-9 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Newton North High School&lt;br /&gt;
Film Lecture Hall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For directions, see this &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/d/edit?mid=zxD5aIyoOQF4.kKJHm1QG3wSY" target="_blank"&gt;map&lt;/a&gt;. 
The Film Lecture Hall is located just off the main school lobby. There should be plenty of parking off of Elm Rd (enter from Lowell or Walnut Streets).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In FLL, teams of up to 10 students, ages 9-14, are immersed in real world science and technology challenges. Teams research and design their own solution to a current scientific question or problem and build autonomous LEGO robots that perform a series of missions. This year's challenge is &lt;a href="http://www.firstlegoleague.org/challenge/2015trashtrek" target="_blank"&gt;Trash Trek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info, you can send an email to &lt;a href="mailto:fll@ligerbots.com"&gt;fll@ligerbots.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>LigerBots Team Info Meeting</title>
<date>2015-06-14 18:06:14</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;The LigerBots, the robotics team of the combined Newton North and South High Schools, is holding an information session for prospective members and parents, tomorrow, Monday June 15th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=\"line-height:1.6\"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=\"line-height:1.6\"&gt; meeting will be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=\"line-height:1.6\"&gt; on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong style=\"line-height:1.6\"&gt;Monday, June 15, 6:30-8:30PM,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style=\"line-height:1.6\"&gt; in the Newton South wood shop, Room 9170. This will be a hands-on evening for prospective team members, with opportunities to drive the 2015 robot, use power tools, CAD on computers, make marketing products, and do engineering challenge games. Mentors will be available to talk with parents about how the team works and opportunities for adult involvement. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=\"line-height:1.6\"&gt;Dessert will be served. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you will be a Newton high school student next year, and are interested in finance, design, community outreach, and even robotics, or are an adult interested in getting involved (non-parents welcome too), please join us and have some fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, email &lt;a href="mailto:info@ligerbots.com" target="_blank"&gt;info@ligerbots.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Parents Night</title>
<date>2015-10-08 21:51:02</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;This Wednesday, October 14th, is LigerBots Parents Night! Parents Night is a special meeting meant for the parents of LigerBots team members to learn everything they need to know about the team. At Parents Night, we will go over the team's structure and schedule, talk about participation requirements, explain rules and procedures, and go over the flow of the year, including our build and competition seasons. We urge at least one parent per family to attend, as the information we will be going over is very important, however we understand if you cannot make it due to prior arrangements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents Night will be held from 7:00 to 8:30, on October 14th in the Film Lecture Hall at North. The film lecture hall is the first room to the left from the Tiger Drive entrance.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>LEGO Robotics Competition Nov 21</title>
<date>2015-11-15 13:43:48</date>
<body>
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="/img/FLL_logo.png" height="160px"&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LigerBots are hosting a FIRST LEGO League (FLL) qualifying tournament at Newton North High School on Saturday, November 21st, from 9am to 3pm. FLL teams have spent the past two months designing and building robots, researching their projects, and practicing their FIRST core values, and are ready to show off their achievements. Come and watch the robot games, see the project presentations in our own 'FLL Idol' event, and explore our mini-Maker's Faire. This event is free and open to the public, and suitable for kids kindergarten age and older!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FLL is part of FIRST (For Inspiration and Recognition of Science and Technology) and is open to students in grades 4-8. FIRST is an international non-profit youth organization created specifically 'to transform our culture by creating a world where science and technology are celebrated and where young people dream of becoming science and technology leaders'. Student participation in the FLL enhances independence and personal growth, while also highlighting skills needed for teamwork and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>New Robot Cameras!</title>
<date>2015-12-03 20:48:01</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;Image processing systems for the Ligerbots have been lacking compared to a few other FIRST Robotics Competition teams in the past few years. Points gained in the short autonomous period given in each FRC game can be critical in determining team standings, and successful image processing is crucial for the robot during the autonomous period. This year we will be trying out one of these &lt;a href="http://www.cctvcameraworld.com/2-megapixel-hd-security-cameras.html"&gt;1080p security cameras&lt;/a&gt;. Network protocol IP security cameras are a cost effective way for our team to integrate video versus going the GroPro route. It is difficult to tap in to the video stream using bluetooth or hdmi for a robotics build, and we hope to use this &lt;a href="http://www.cctvcameraworld.com/using-ip-cameras-blue-iris-software/"&gt;IP camera using its RTSP stream&lt;/a&gt; to access the video stream over the network. With this camera we hope to develop our image processing capabilities through the use of the OpenCV library or the LabView image processing module, and we hope to develop a successful image processing system for the upcoming FRC game. We will update this page later with our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Weekly Update: December 6th</title>
<date>2015-12-13 14:29:34</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;This was a busy and productive week for the Ligerbots. Our awards team is deciding which awards we will be applying for and which students will be helping with each application. The business team talked about heraldry, an important part of this year's game, and they also discussed the creation of sponsor levels. The three mechanical teams: 2014 rebuild, 2015 disassembly, and the robot arm, all made big strides this week towards finishing. Everyone has been doing great work and we are all excited for the start of build season.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Weekly Update: Happy Holidays!</title>
<date>2015-12-21 09:09:43</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;We are closing in on the final weeks before build season. The business team is continuing the heraldry brainstorm and are finalizing sponsor levels. The mechanical team finished the 2015 disassembly and is on the final stretch of finishing the rebuild of the 2014 robot. The robotic arm group is in the middle of construction and hopes to finish before the build season begins. The Ligerbots are looking forward to a great season and we would like to wish everyone a happy holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Stronghold Kickoff This Saturday</title>
<date>2016-01-06 20:35:22</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;The Kickoff for the 2016 FRC game, called Stronghold, is this Saturday at 10:30 AM EST. If you can not make it to an official event, you can watch it &quot;live&quot; via the website &lt;a href="http://corporate.comcast.com/news-information/news-feed/2016-first-robotics-competition-kickoff" target="_blank"&gt;http://corporate.comcast.com/news-information/news-feed/2016-first-robotics-competition-kickoff&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Build Season has started!</title>
<date>2016-01-10 19:54:46</date>
<body>

&lt;img alt="STRONGHOLD Kickoff" src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1650/23981257269_95967520c7.jpg" style="float:right; height:400px; margin:0 0 0 30px" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build season is finally under way! The game has been released and we are gearing up for our best season ever. FIRST Stronghold is a medieval themed game that includes tackling a variety of defenses to score in the opponent's castle. We have broken up into design teams to theorize game strategy and possible design ideas. Everyone is excited to present their ideas later in the week and for the season as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear="all"/&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Build Season: End of Week 1</title>
<date>2016-01-18 17:05:15</date>
<body>

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img alt="CADding Session" title="CADding Session" src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1597/24436703926_dc1d240842_z_d.jpg" 
     style="width:400px; margin:0 30px 0 0;" align="left"/&gt;
It has been just over a week into build season and the LigerBots have been doing a lot of amazing stuff. The Awards group is continuing their work on the Chairman's Award and Safety Animation. The Business team is preparing for the Just Think Expo and the Horace Mann Science Fair. The Mechanical team has been working hard on prototyping and finalizing a design for the robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we tried a new brainstorming technique. We broke up into six teams and each team designed a robot individually. Then each group presented their designs and we took the best parts from each robot. This was a great success as it allowed everyone on our team to have a say in the design. Overall, we have had a great start to build season and we cannot wait to see our robot develop into its finished product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear="all"/&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>More Build Season News</title>
<date>2016-01-28 16:14:45</date>
<body>
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SAO6ZXI-9yI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LigerBot's Build Season has been amazing so far! The awards group submitted the safety animation project this week in addition to continuing their work on the Chairman's Award. The business team wrote thank you notes to sponsors and donors. Finally, the mechanical team is putting the final touches on the design of the robot as well as prototyping and milling the parts and mechanisms on the robot.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Build Season: Lots of Stuff Being Done</title>
<date>2016-02-01 16:07:55</date>
<body>

&lt;img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1459/24737530036_fd6fc9b09f.jpg" alt="STRONGHOLD Kickoff"
  title="STRONGHOLD Kickoff" style="float:right; width:400px; margin:0 0 0 30px" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow! It it has been an amazing three weeks so far, we are past the halfway point of build season! The Awards group is working on two major projects. They have finished the short answer and are beginning their work on the essay for the Chairman's Award. In addition, we have been drafting the essay for the Woodie Flowers, which is an award for mentors who demonstrate the mission of FIRST. The business team finalized the shield and standard selections for the heraldry portion of this year's game, as well as continuing their work on writing thank you notes to our sponsors. The mechanical team has continued working towards the completion of the robot. The programming team worked on the vision tracking program while electrical finished hooking up the talons and the LEDs. Furthermore, we have gotten the CNC up and running, finalized the design, and begun cutting components for the shooter and almost finished the chassis. We also have cut the chassis pieces for the second robot. It has been wonderful three weeks so far and we are looking forward to the next three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear="all" /&gt;

</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Shark Ninja!</title>
<date>2016-02-02 17:11:44</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Shark Ninja Mentoring" src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1595/24137074313_27f77c7039_z_d.jpg" style="float:left; margin:0 30px 0 0; width:400px" /&gt; This year, we have the benefit of adding a sponsor, starting what we hope to be the first of many build seasons together.  &lt;a href="http://www.sharkninja.com"&gt;Shark Ninja&lt;/a&gt; has an office here in Newton and has offered the team support in a variety of ways not the least of which includes several employees joining us as mentors.  This is what one student had to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Shark Ninja has recently sponsored and mentored Ligerbots.  I have been lucky enough to work with some of the nice people from Shark Ninja. I have mainly worked with Justin, who has helped me out a lot. I am new to LigerBots and am not familiar with a lot of the tasks that I am asked to complete. Justin has gladly helped me out. It is really cool to learn what older people doing in the same field. I am very glad to have worked with Justin and the rest of the people at Shark Ninja. &quot; - A Freshmen of the NNHS Class of 2019 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>FLL STEM Literature Month</title>
<date>2016-02-02 22:26:08</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;STEM (Science Technology Engineering and Mathematics) is becoming increasingly important in society. Every aspect of our lives is touched by it to some extent, even the most mundane tasks. From the coffee we buy in the morning to the smartphone that receives the snapchat of that coffee, STEM is intimately involved in everything we do. Like many of the important things in life, we tend to take it for granted, benefiting from its presence without showing gratitude. One of the main goals of both FIRST (For Inspiration and Recognition of Science and Technology) and the LigerBots is to spread appreciation of STEM in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    The purpose of this writing contest for FLL students is just that: Appreciating STEM in our own communities by recognising local Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics companies and ventures. The goal of this activity is to share what is happening that is new and exciting in STEM locally. Because there is so much happening, we have taken the whole month of February to celebrate STEM, declaring it STEM Literature Month. Each week of February will be dedicated to the four parts of STEM: Science week - February 1st -  7th ; Technology Week - February 8th - 14th ; Engineering Week - February 15th - 21st ; Mathematics Week - February 22nd - 28th. During each of these weeks FLL students will be asked to submit a short essay, no longer than a page, to the LigerBots describing how a local venture or company embodies the aspect of STEM being celebrated that week. Each week, the essay that best represents that week's aspect of STEM will be posted on the LigerBots website and the author of the essay will receive a prize&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Essays must be submitted by 3 pm EST on the Sunday of each week. Essays must be no shorter than half a page and no longer than one page.They must focus on one local company or venture and how it represents new and exciting things going on in our community. Writing must be the student's own work! Submissions must be complete with student name and FLL affiliation. FIRST is about spreading STEM, but it is also about fun - learn a lot, have fun, and we look forwards to reading your submissions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submissions can be sent to info@ligerbots.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Last Week of Build Season!</title>
<date>2016-02-16 15:13:44</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;Build season is almost up and we are working hard to finish the robot. 
We have the robot driving and many of the other components are working. 
Programming is beginning to work with the robot to finish the drive program. 
The second robot team has almost completed the chassis.
We have a feeling this will be a great year and hope to make it farther in the competition than last year. 
In addition, the awards group has finished the Woodie Flowers Award and the Chairman's Award. 
Many students are also working hard writing grants. 
We plan to make a lot of progress this week in building our robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1564/24629252920_dcf2dff4da_z_d.jpg" height="420px" /&gt;
   
&lt;img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1462/24806824572_65bbe66e4b.jpg" height="420px" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Build Season: Coming to an End</title>
<date>2016-02-22 22:16:28</date>
<body>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Robot 2016" src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1543/25106663826_258eb479c0_z_d.jpg" style="float:right; margin:0 0 0 30px; width:640px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build season finishes this Tuesday, February 23rd. We worked very hard on the robot last week, gaining a ton of progress on many of our goals. This year we worked hard on designing some awesome mechanisms to work with the different defenses - creating a very interesting robot. We have had a great build season and cannot wait for our first competition in early March. Currently we are putting on the final touches before we bag it tomorrow. Last Sunday, we went to a BU practice field to test many of our parts, and get some driving practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The business team worked hard on creating graphics, finalizing projects, and working on prestigious awards such as the Chairman's Award. They also finalized the design of our iconic tie-dye t-shirt for this year. The whole team has been working very hard on many different projects this build season with the team creating many well-polished designs, projects, and pitches. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br clear="all"&gt;
</body>
</data>

<data>
<title>Almost on to our first competition!</title>
<date>2016-03-05 13:52:19</date>
<body>
&lt;img src="https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1582/25145997952_33bdd80b1b_z_d.jpg" alt="Second Robot" title="Second Robot" style="float:left; height:360px; width:640px; margin:0 30px 0 0"/&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build season is finished and we have continued to work hard on finishing the second robot. The chassis is done and most of the electronics are mounted and wired. We just need to put on the treads before we can drive. In addition, programming has been working on the vision code for shooting. On Thursday, the 3rd, the Ligerbots were at newton north high school for student night. Everything is looking great and we can not wait for our first competition next week at WPI!&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
</data>
</posts>
